

Seongyong Park

RESEARCH SCIENTIST · SYNERGISTIC BIOINFORMATICS LAB

KAIST 291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, Rep. of KOREA

□ (+82) 10-4718-4967 | sypark0215@kaist.ac.kr | psychemistz.github.io/profile | psychemistz

"Things which we see are not by themselves what we see... It remains completely unknown to us what the objects may be by themselves and apart from the receptivity of our senses. We know nothing but our manner of perceiving them." **Immanuel Kant**

Summary

I have over 7 years of experience in bioinformatics and machine learning. In the meantime, I managed 'Multi-Component and Multi-Target (MCMT) drug discovery from Traditional Korean Medicine' project and initiated 'Developing AI model for cancer drug discovery' projects for Synergistic Bioinformatics Lab at KAIST. I managed databases related to the bioinformatic/chemoinformatic discovery and closely interact with experimental lab's members who verify prediction of biomarkers and candidate drugs. I designed computational methods to harmonize prior knowledge of disease gene, biological network, disease mechanism associated gene sets and gene expression datasets of patient/model organisms. I managed CPU/GPU clusters to perform high-performance computing (HPC) too.

My major research topic for MCMT project is developing computational methods to optimize gene expression marker set to explain clinical and model organism responses at the same time, by utilizing the prior knowledge related to the disease mechanisms. I have co-authored several patents and peer-reviewed articles related to bioinformatics and machine/deep learning. For bioinformatic applications, I studied gene expression based prognostic model development, assay oriented marker set optimization, drug-target interaction prediction and drug repurposing. I'm also interested in applying statistial/machine/deep learning in various other topics such as application of overlap statistics, sequence based protein classification, protein-protein interaction prediction, spectral signal processing including ElectroEncehpaloGraphy (EEG) and Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy (SERS).

Work Experience

Synergistic Bioinformatics Lab, KAIST.

Daejeon, S.Korea

Ph.D. Research Scholar

(Aug. 2015 - -)

- research, design and implement algorithms in graph theory, machine learning and deep learning for development of gene expression based diagnostic & prognostic models and drug candidate prediction models.
- apply theoretical expertise and innovation to generate patents and publications in top-ranked journals.
- · using wide range of tools to acquire information and interpret data, writing up reports and presenting finding.

Synergistic Bioinformatics Lab, KAIST.

Daejeon, S.Korea

RESEARCHER

Aug. 2014 - Aug, 2015

- research, design and implement algorithms in graph theory, machine learning and deep learning for development of gene expression based diagnostic & prognostic models and drug candidate prediction models.
- apply theoretical expertise and innovation to generate patents and publications in top-ranked journals.
- · using wide range of tools to acquire information and interpret data, writing up reports and presenting finding.

Biobrain Inc.

Daejeon, S.Korea Aug. 2012 - Aug, 2014

RESEARCHER

research, design and implement biosignal processing algorithms for EEG applications.

· using wide range of tools to acquire information and interpret data, writing up reports and presenting finding.

Planning and Evaluation Office, Korea Institute of Energy Technology Evaluation and Planning (KETEP).

Seoul, S.Korea

RESEARCHER

Feb. 2012 - Aug, 2012

- Evaluation of research project associated with renewable energy.
- · writing research trend reports.
- attending staff meetings and general administration.

Skills

Expertise Bioinformatics, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Network Science, Signal Processing

Programming R, Python, MATLAB, TensorFlow, Keras, Pytorch, LaTeX

Languages Korean, English

March 25, 2022 Seongyong Park · Curriculum Vitae



Patents & Patent Applications

- 1. Bumki Min, Gwansu Yi and **Seongyong Park**. "System and method for disease prediction based on group marker consisting of genes having similar function." *KR. Patent* 1022361940000, *App.* 1020200145453, issued Mar 30, 2021. [online]
- Taesung Kim and Seongyong Park. "Microfluidic concentrator array for observing predation behavior of microbes." KR. Patent 1012385560000, App. 1020100110945, issued Febrary 22, 2013. [online]
- 3. Taesung Kim and **Seongyong Park**. "Microfluidic concentrator for communication assays of microbes." **KR. Patent 1013304730000, App. 1020110073766,** issued Febrary **04, 2013.** [online]

Peer-Reviewed Journal Papers

- 1. **Seongyong Park**, Gwansu Yi*. "Development of Gene Expression-Based Random Forest Model for Predicting Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy Response in Triple-Negative Breast Cancer" *Cancers*, Febrary, 2022, [online]
- 2. **Seongyong Park**, Jaeseok Lee, Shujaat Khan, Abdul Wahab, Minseok Kim*. "SERSNet: Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy based Bio-Molecule Detection using Deep Neural Network" *Biosensors*, November, 2021, [online]
- 3. **Seongyong Park**, Jaeseok Lee, Shujaat Khan, Abdul Wahab, Minseok Kim*. "Machine Learning-based Heavy Metal Ion Detection Using Surface-Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy" *Sensors*, January, 2022, [online]
- 4. Muhammad Usman, Shujaat Khan*, **Seongyong Park**, Abdul Wahab. "AFP-SRC: Identification of Antifreeze Proteins Using Sparse Representation Classifier." *Neural Computing and Applications*, September. 2021, [online]
- 5. Muhammad Usman, Shujaat Khan, **Seongyong Park**, Jeong-A Lee*. "AoP-LSE: Antioxidant Proteins Classification Using Deep Latent Space Encoding of Sequence Features." *Current Issues in Molecular Biology: (Bioinformatics and Systems Biology section)*, October. 2021, [online]
- 6. Yoon Hyeok Lee, Hojae Choi, **Seongyong Park**, Boah Lee, Gwansu Yi*. "Drug repositioning for enzyme modulator based on human metabolite-likeness" **BMC Bioinformatics**, May, 2017, [online]
- 7. Sung Min Kim, **Seongyong Park**, Jong Won Hong, Eu Jean Jang, Chun Ho Pak*. "Psychophysiological Effects of Orchid and Rose Fragrances on Humans" *Hortic Sci Technol*, June, 2016, [online]
- 8. Woon Sun Choi, Dogyeong Ha, **Seongyong Park**, Taesung Kim*. "Synthetic multicellular cell-to-cell communication in inkjet printed bacterial cell systems" *Biomaterials*, April, 2011, [online]
- 9. **Seongyong Park**, Dasol Kim, Robert J Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "A microfluidic concentrator array for quantitative predation assays of predatory microbes" *Lab on a Chip*, September, 2011, [online]
- 10. Vinuselvi Parisutham, **Seongyong Park**, Minseok Kim, Jung Min Park, Taesung Kim, Sung Kuk Lee*. "Microfluidic Technologies for Synthetic Biology" *Int J Mol Sci.*, December, 2011, [online]
- 11. Woon Sun Choi, Minseok Kim, **Seongyong Park**, Sung Kuk Lee, Taesung Kim*. "Microfabricated ratchet structure integrated concentrator arrays for synthetic bacterial cell-to-cell communication assays" *Lab on a Chip*, January, 2012 [online]
- 12. **Seongyong Park**, Xiaoqiang Hong, Woon Sun Choi, Taesung Kim*. "Microfabricated ratchet structure integrated concentrator arrays for synthetic bacterial cell-to-cell communication assays" *Lab on a Chip*, June, 2012, [online]

Abstracts, Posters and Conference Proceedings

- Seongyong Park, Shujaat Khan*, Muhammad Moinuddin, Ubaid M. Al-Saggaf. "GSSMD: A new standardized effect size measure to improve robustness and interpretability in biological applications," in 2020 IEEE International Conference on Bioinformatics and Biomedicine (BIBM), Seoul, Korea (South), 2020, pp. 1096-1099, [online]
- 2. **Seongyong Park**, Dasol Kim, Robert J. Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "A Microfluidic Concentrator Array for Studying Predatory Bacterial Microbes." in *MicroTAS*. 2010, *Groningen*, *Netherland*.
- 3. **Seongyong Park**, Xiaoqiang Hong, Minseok Kim, Woon Sun Choi, Taesung Kim*. "Bacterial Cell-to-cell Communication Assays in A Micro-fabricated Concentrator Array Device." in *MicroTAS*. 2011, Seattle, USA.
- 4. **Seongyong Park**, Xiaoqiang Hong, Minseok Kim, Woon Sun Choi, Taesung Kim*. "Bacterial Cell-to-cell Communication Assays in A Micro-fabricated Concentrator Array Device." in *ISMM. 2011, Seoul, Korea.*
- 5. **Seongyong Park**, Dasol Kim, Robert J. Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "A Bacteria-on-a-chip: Understanding on the Predation Rate of Predatory Prokaryotes." in *Biochip. 2010, Seoul, S.Korea.*
- 6. **Seongyong Park**, Sunjang Lee, Dasol Kim, Robert J. Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "High Throughput Screening of Predatory Bacterial Microbes using Chemotaxis." in *KSME Spring Conference on Bioengineering Division. 2010, Jeju, S.Korea.*
- 7. **Seongyong Park**, Dasol Kim, Robert J. Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "A Microfluidic Concentrator Array for Quantifying Predation by Predatory Microbes Toward Its Prey." in *Biochip. 2011, Ulsan, S.Korea.*
- 8. **Seongyong Park**, Sunjang Lee, Dasol Kim, Robert J. Mitchell, Taesung Kim*. "Bacterial Cell-to-Cell Communication Assays in Microfabricated Concentrator Array Device." in *KSME Spring Conference on Bioengineering Division. 2011, Pohang, S.Korea.*

Pre-Prints & In-Review

- 1. **Seongyong Park**, Mohammad Sohail Ibrahim, Abdul Wahab, Shujaat Khan*. "GMDM: A generalized multi-dimensional distribution overlap metric for data and model quality evaluation." In revision: *Neural Compting and Applications*, (since Feb. 2022). [online]
- 2. **Seongyong Park**, Abdul Wahab, Shujaat Khan*. "E3-targetPred: Prediction of E3-target proteins using deep latent space encoding." In revision: *IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics*, (since May. 2021). [online]
- 3. **Seongyong Park**, Shujaat Khan*. "A Novel Metric for Robust and Interpretable Bioassay Applications." In revision: **Statistical Methods & Applications**, (since Mar. 2022). [online]

In-Preparation

- 1. **Seongyong Park**, Shujaat Khan, Abdul Wahab, Minseok Kim*. "Self-Supervised learning for Inter-laboratory Variation Minimization in Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy" To be submitted
- 2. **Seongyong Park**, Jaeseok Lee, Abdul Wahab, Shujaat Khan, Minseok Kim*. "Machine Learning based Cadmium detection in Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy" In Preparation
- 3. Seongyong Park*, Shujaat Khan. "ovltools: An R package to estimate distribution overlap between two arbitrary distributions." To be submitted

Education

KAIST(Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea

Aug. 2015 - -

Ph.D. in Bio & Brain Engineering

• Got the KAIST student scholarship which is given to promising students.

UNIST(Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology)

Ulsan, S.Korea

Mar. 2010 - Feb. 2012

M.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

- Thesis: Microfluidic Concentrator Array for Quantitative Predation Study of Predatory Microbes [online]
- Got the UNIST student scholarship which is given to promising students.

PKNU (Pukyung National University)

Busan, S.Korea

B.E. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Mar. 2002 - Feb. 2010

• Got BK21 scholarships which are given to top-ranked students in each Dept.